# Eric Delmer Millen

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ericdelmermillen@gmail.com +1 647-671-0836

<u>linkedin.com/eric-delmer-millen</u> github.com/ericdelmermillen

#### **PROFILE**

Energetic tech enthusiast with experience working in team environments. My previous experience, both within the entrepreneurial world, as well as in working in health and wellness has helped me become a strong communicator with an eye to detail and team dynamics.

I am driven by working on and being able to contribute to the building of meaningful technological solutions to human-centered problems.

## **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, User Authentication OAuth, AWS (S3, EC2, Amplify), Web APIs, Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, Figma, Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

#### SELECTED EXPERIENCE

# UI/UX Designer, Project Manager | LookingList Personals

FEB 2019 - MAY 2023, TORONTO, ON

- Design of Personal Ads Style Mobile dating app and promotional site
- User research testing from interviews through prototype stage
- Project management including planning sprints and hiring and managing subcontractors and software testing.

# **Business Consultant | AE Business Consultancy**

JUL 2014 - OCT 2016, LONDON, UK

 Drafted contracts, business plans and other business documents for business clients with low-level English.

# **ESL/EFL Teacher** | Various Schools

JUL 2009 - AUG 2014, LONDON, UK / TORONTO, ON

- Taught English at various levels including Academic English,
  CAE/FCE/IELTS and one on one executive language tutoring.
- Lead week-long Teacher Training Seminars for Content Language Integrated Learning (CLIL) for Oxford International English School.

#### **EDUCATION**

# BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

JUN 2023 - SEPT 2023, TORONTO, ON

#### Coventry / Trinity International | TESOL / CERT TESOL

APR 2009 - JUN 2009, TORONTO, ON

# McMaster University | Bachelor of Arts, English Literature

SEPT 2003 - APR 2009, HAMILTON, ON

Dean's Honor List 2006-2007

## **PROJECTS**

# Full Stack Custom Portfolio Web App | Amithamakeupartist.com

June 2024, CUSTOM MAKEUP ARTIST RECT APP WITH ADMIN CMS

- Web app portfolio site with custom CMS for Makeup Artist client
- Includes Express server, MySQL Database and AWS services (S3 Bucket, EC2 Ubuntu Server, Amplify hosting for React front end).

#### Capstone Project | Mad Gabs Game

Sept 2023, BRAINSTATION SOFTWARE ENGINEERING DIPLOMA PROJECT

- React web app utilizing react web speech API to enable users to play the classic word game "Mad Gabs" via Voice input
- Includes Google SSO via Passport.js, Express server and MySQL Database